What do you lean on mentally when you
get overwhelmed?
>> Music,
exercise,
really great movies.
You have to be able to just completely
shut it off and do something totally
different. I recommend to people all the
time
music, exercise, and movies. Immerse
yourself. Go to the gym. Go for a run.
Listen to an hour or two of
uninterrupted music. You know,
headphones. Don't answer the phone.
Don't surf the the internet.
Just do something for yourself.
And it's hard, you know, everybody's
busy. Everybody's
wired electronically to different
devices and it's hard, but it's
important.
>> What's your go-to like music or a movie
to watch if you've just gotten in like a
war with somebody on Twitter?
>> Don't laugh at me.
Um but
I listen to
a lot of classic rock.
Mostly early to mid-70s classic rock.
Um I listen to folk
specifically from the 30s and 40s and
50s.
And more than anything else probably I
listen to Greek music. There's a There's
a genre of Greek music that came out of
the prisons and the opium dens of
Constantinople around the turn of the
20th century called Rebetika.
It's a Greek like blues is is the way
most people describe it. And um and
mostly I listen to that.
>> So the classic rock like Zeppelin, the
Eagles, stuff like that?
>> Definitely. Definitely.
Love it.
>> What's your workout routine like to keep
your mind sane?
>> O- Only in the last year I've gotten so
busy that I finally gave up my gym
membership.
But um now I go I go for very long
walks.
But I I go with earbuds so I'm not
distracted by by people or by traffic or
things like that. So, I do a lot of
walking.
Um before I used to I used to go to the
gym
almost every day.
Yeah. And you start, you know, 15
minutes on the treadmill just to warm up
and then you got to do you got to do
weights. It's all about muscle tone.
You don't want to just shrivel up and
you know,
blow away.
>> How important do you think uh exercise
and your overall health is
um for things like mindset, confidence?
>> Critical. Absolutely critical.
Um
you almost can't work at the CIA and not
have PTSD.
In fact, I I've got a buddy
we go to the same church, we're in the
same men's group, and we also worked at
the CIA together.
And consummate overachiever. He's also a
brigadier general in the army and a
psychiatrist.
Yeah, so he's done everything.
And he said to me one time,
"I find it fascinating
that you came back from Pakistan with no
PTSD,
but you have crippling PTSD from your
divorce."
And I said, "I allowed myself,
despite my training,
to trust one person,
and that was the person who betrayed
me."
He diagnosed me with something called
moral injury, which is a a relatively
new diagnosis. It appears in the DSM-6.
And um
I had never heard of it. I had to look
it up.
And what it comes down to is if you're
raised in a certain
way
to believe that these things are right
and these things are wrong, and the
wrong things you just don't do, and then
somebody does it to you.
Your brain cannot wrap itself around the
fact that this has been done to you.
And it leads to PTSD.
>> From what I've gathered, it was it was a
very high conflict divorce, very
stressful for you.
And which So, would you
kind of agree in the fact that that
situation was harder than everything you
went through with leaving the CIA?
>> Oh, my my divorce was the was the worst
thing I ever went through in my life.
Far, far worse than prison, far worse
than being arrested and
and yeah, any of that stuff. Far more
difficult than going after Al-Qaeda or
the Iranians or Hezbollah or
any of the things I ever did at the CIA.
>> And just because of the the moral
part of it for you.
>> Yeah, you want to you want to have like
one person in life that you can trust.
Just one.
Is that asking too much?
Yeah, I never thought so.
>> I think that people have a hard time
dealing with stress and anxiety.
Um
what are some of your tips for
how people can not get overwhelmed when
things aren't going their way?
>> Yeah, you've got to This is one of the
things that they taught us at the
agency, too. You've got to do things for
yourself.
You know,
take up a hobby. I have no hobbies. I
honest to god, I'm not just blowing
smoke here. I'm the hardest working
person I know.
I I work easily 16 hours a day. I
actually set my alarm for 4:00 a.m. just
so I can answer Cameo requests until
7:00, and then start my regular work
day.
Um
but I have no hobbies. I used to, but I
don't. So, I decided to take up a hobby.
I took up astrophotography, right?
Photographing the planets and then
nebula and galaxies and stuff like that.
And it requires great patience.
And so that's actually worked out for
me.
But, you know, go get a massage, go to
the gym,
go go swimming at the YMCA or whatever.
Do something. Go biking, you know, now
electronic bikes are everywhere. There's
no reason that everybody shouldn't be
biking.
Because you don't even have to pedal
uphill anymore. It's all electronic.
So, you got to do something for
yourself. You got to block off time for
yourself. Otherwise, you burn out and
you go crazy.
>> What about like if something
stressful happens like in the moment?
Like how can people zone out from that?
>> Yeah. You know, three people over the
last 3 days have recommended meditation
to me.
Um I've never I've never meditated. My
brother swears by it.
And other people that I've spoken to say
it's the greatest thing that that they
ever took up. So, there there's got to
be something to it. You know, there's
something that's popular in my area
right now and it's these um
stretching clinics.
Right? Where you pay like 50 bucks and
then they stretch the heck out of your
body.
And I'm told that that is like supremely
relaxing and excellent. I haven't tried
it myself. I will say that I've broken
the piggy bank and I've
I've gone to get massages for the very
first time in my life.
And there
I I'm not even sure I can come up with
something that is
more satisfying
and
feels better than getting a massage.
>> I mean, you've been through so much.
Like have you gone to therapy or
anything to deal with some of the
trauma?
>> Oh, absolutely.
Absolutely.
It's funny. I like I said, I never had
PTSD from from the agency. Never.
Um but my divorce just destroyed me.
>> Like, what's your mission now? Like, I
mean, is your main is your main mission
now what you're doing with the podcast
and and interviews and speaking about
like current events?
>> Yes, I've been extraordinarily fortunate
in the last 8 weeks or so
in that I gave an interview to uh
to Steven uh Bartlett at uh Diary of a
CEO.
And a 20-year-old sophomore from the
University of Texas at Austin took that
interview and chopped it up into shorts
and gave me an Alvin and the Chipmunks
voice and had laser beams shooting out
of my eyes.
All in good fun.
And it
just went crazy
viral on TikTok
to the point where I'm not exaggerating
when I tell you I can't walk 25 ft down
the street without somebody stopping me
and asking for a selfie. And I always
say yes.
Always. I flew from Miami last night to
Washington. I got stopped five times at
the airport and twice on the plane
and asked for selfies.
So
out of that came
representation by a major talent agency.
Um
invitations for
speeches and you know, new publishing
deals and
I'm wrapped in Hollywood. Um
I'm going to be the spokesman for, you
know, this company or that company or
the other company. It's just my whole
life has changed in the last 8 weeks.
So the anchor of that is is my podcast.
And um
and I've got my books.
For many years as as a hobby until a
couple of years ago when I ran out of
time, I would write television pilots
and I've been fortunate enough to sell
eight of them over the last 20 years in
Hollywood, so I've I've got a manager
and an agent and an entertainment
attorney and
that's fun to do. So, I'm just going to
keep writing and podcasting and speaking
and
and call that my career.